This industry has has tailwinds for the
first time, not headwinds. I want to ask
you about the crypto stockpile, about
the choices they made.
The reason that those were actually
brought up
The SPR and digital assets
initiative was signed to executive
action a couple of weeks ago. What is
the timeline of implementation? This is
what we need to do to deliver on the
president's promises to welcome in the
golden age for digital assets in the
United States to make the United States
the crypto capital of the planet. We
certainly want to acquire more. I've had
you know people ask me how much do you
guys want to have? I'm like that's like
asking a country how much gold they want
to have.
The only thing I want to know about
Trump does he
We're here now with Bo Hines at the
digital asset summit. He's the executive
director of the president's council of
economic advisors on digital assets. I'm
David Lin this is Morning Trade. Welcome
to the show. Thank you very much for
having me. I want to ask you about the
crypto stockpile, about the choices they
made. What's the rationale behind ADA,
Solana, Ethereum? Well first I I I think
we should talk about the SPR first and
it's kind of how you know why we set it
up the way that we did. I mean we view
Bitcoin as being unique. Bitcoin is a
commodity not a security. It has
intrinsic stored value. It has you know
the immaculate conception as as David
likes to describe it meaning that
there's no issue or so you know it
stands in its own class. We view it as
digital gold and we want to acquire as
much of it as we can for the American
people on a budget neutral way that
doesn't cost the taxpayer a dime. You
know I think it's really important to
note that you know under this
president's leadership he's actually
working on acquiring assets for the
American people rather than taking it
away.
And to answer your question about the
the digital assets national stockpile,
you know I think that we welcome
innovation in the space across multiple
ecosystems. We want to see the US really
dominate the space in terms of digital
technological financial innovation.
And so with that you know the reason
that those were actually brought up you
know they're just the top five biggest
market caps. I mean there's there's
there's pretty simple explanation for
it. But with that being said you know
there's going to be continued innovation
here in the United States as it relates
to all these ecosystems across many
different platforms and we want to make
sure that all of these actors can
continue to thrive and grow their
businesses.
The SPR and digital assets
initiative was signed to executive
action a couple of weeks ago. What is
the timeline of implementation do you
know?
Well the work let's go back to the
president's first EO executive order on
digital assets which was a day three
priority for the administration. You
know it lays out some crucial landmarks.
We're at the 30-day landmark with the
interagency working group which David
Sax is the chair and I'm the executive
director over.
That landmark basically asked all of
these agencies to do an internal audit
or review
of everything that touched digital
assets within their agencies. They
produced those reports. We've come
through them and now we're approaching
the 60-day landmark in which we're
asking these interagency actors and
other White House offices that are part
of this group to produce
recommendations. And what we'll do
together is compile a report for the
president to meet the 120-day landmark
in which it's comprehensive and we say
this is what we need to do to deliver on
the president's promises to welcome in
the golden age for digital assets in the
United States to make the United States
the crypto capital of the planet.
And you know part of that is what the
president outlined at the summit last
week. We have to get rid of any rules
that undergird operation choke point 2.0
that have stifled you know institutional
banks' ability to interact with digital
asset firms.
Is that actually proof of that in the
works or has happened? Oh I mean look at
what Hester's done at the SEC over the
course of the past few weeks. Look at
what the OCC did I think two Fridays
ago.
You know this is this is well in the
works. Then you pair that with what's
going on with legislation on the hill.
We had a stablecoin just got out of
Senate Banking Committee with an 18 to
six bipartisan vote. You know this
industry has
tailwinds for the first time not
headwinds. I mean this is a space that
at least in the United States has been
beaten down kicked down over the last
decade and a half specifically under the
Biden regulatory regime. They were
victims of warfare. They were treated
differently than any other industry has
ever been treated in the history of the
United States and it's high time that
that changes. And so between interagency
activity between what's happening with
Congress you know we hope to act as the
administrator and or sherpa between
White House policy industry interagency
and what's happening on the hill so we
can deliver on the president's promises.
Do you think Bitcoin reserve is a
potential boost for USD meaning more
people are going to buy Bitcoin and that
results in more people buying T-bills?
Well you know I I think that Bitcoin
being the grandfather that it is is
oftentimes you know from a retail
investment side the first purchase that
the people have made. But look we're not
financial advisors and I would you know
instruct anyone that's considering
buying any
asset class in the crypto space to you
know consult a financial advisor for the
details. This is a naturally volatile
market and we understand that.
But you know the grand scheme of things
I I feel as if the United States is
finally in the forefront of leading the
charge in terms of global adoption and
knitting the gap between institutional
banking and digital asset technology.
And Bitcoin plays a huge role in that
just because of the nature of the way
that it's set. So
you know with the SPR I think it's just
a monumental step forward in the sense
of recognizing it for what it is which
is digital gold. You know the president
talked about or David's talked about
putting the digital Fort Knox around
that and what it looks like.
You know I think stable's honestly to
answer your question will probably drive
US dollar dominance globally as we see
people start to actually have access to
payment rails that are instantaneous in
the way that financial marketplaces
work. But all of these things come
together to create a new financial
marketplace. Will the taxpayers pay for
the SPR?
No and that was outlined specifically in
the EO. These have to be budget neutral
ways of acquisition. There are countless
ways in which we can do this. I've heard
many great ideas over the last couple of
weeks. Senator Lummis has in the Bitcoin
Act one interesting idea which is
realizing the value of gold certificates
from the 1970s that are now worth a lot
more today. You could take you know the
difference there and apply that to
acquiring more Bitcoin. But that's just
one idea. That's just one that's
publicly out there. I mean we have as
the president likes to say very high IQ
people working on this stuff and I The
government's not going to buy new
Bitcoin it's it's already Bitcoin that
they own through acquisition through
illegal you know channels. Is that that
what it is? Well that's currently what
we have. But the
EO has instructed us to look in at
creative opportunities to acquire more
in this budget neutral ways that won't
cost the taxpayer. So I mean there's
there's a lot of different ways you can
do this. You know currently it's it's
tasked Secretary of Treasury Secretary
of Commerce in order to look at these
creative innovative ways that we can
accomplish this goal. But we certainly
want to acquire more. I've had you know
people ask me how much do you guys want
to have? I'm like that's like asking a
country how much gold they want to have
right?
You know we we want to do it in a way
that benefits the American people and
continue to push this along.
The only thing I want to know about
Trump does he really like McDonald's?
How much fast food do you have in the
White House? You know I have not seen
any fast food wrappers around the White
House but I know that I know the
president
you know he's he's certainly keen on
McDonald's when he's traveling. I've
seen that just like many of you have
publicly. But
you know I just want to thank him for
his leadership in the space because if
it weren't for him if it weren't for
everything that he's gone through
over the course of the last really eight
eight to nine years we wouldn't be in
this place as an industry today for
digital assets and none of us would have
the ability to drive this you know
change forward here in the United
States.
going to be one of the youngest economic
advisors or advisors overall. Well it's
a privilege. I mean going to work every
day at the White House is an immense
privilege that we have to take very
seriously. And you know I I understand
when I step foot on the Navy steps every
day and go to my office that you know
I'm there to work on behalf of the
American people and deliver for them.
And to enact the president's priorities
in which you know there was an absolute
mandate for him to be elected and it's
time that that we enact what he wants to
do.
All right. Well thank you very much Bo.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.